Chris Elkington

Email: cpelkington2216@gmail.com

Phone: 07498-099695

Personal Statement

I have recently returned to the UK after two years spent working in an IT capacity in the non-profit sector in Canada. I am keen to bring my previous experiences in IT solutions & data management to a new enterprise.

I am a confident problem solver that prides myself on being able to think swiftly and logically in stressful situations. I have proven myself in the start of my career working both in small teams and individually both in a customer-facing and internal capacity.

Skills

- Advanced Excel
- Dynamics 365 CRM/ERP applications
- Experience in SQL, Python, HTML
- Office365 Administration experience

Education

- Bachelors of Science in Mathematics Keele University 2017

 Course highlights: Data analysis, technical report writing, data modelling, public speaking/presenting, medical statistics, mathematical biology and cryptography.
- A-levels East Leake Academy, Nottinghamshire 2014
 Maths, Chemistry, Physics and Biology

Employment

Systems Coordinator Special Olympics Alberta - Edmonton, Canada

Aug 2018 - Mar 2020

- Administered our Microsoft Dynamics CRM databases hosted through Office 365
 - o Created dashboards and statistical reports
 - Created training material and conducted training sessions to guide staff members on how to use Dynamics
- Managed our online registration portal
 - Regularly coordinated with third-party software engineers to continually develop the system
 - O Developed training material and ran webinars and in-person seminars for volunteers with varying levels of IT literacy

- Conducted feedback surveys that were personalized to a variety of different types of end-user to gauge the user-friendliness and effectiveness of the system
- Revised the procedure for tracking stats to align better with our quarterly and annual goals and used Excel Macros to increase efficiency of processes with which these stats were tracked
- Organised the replacement of all PCs and a variety of other hardware within the office
- Migrated all share folders onto SharePoint Online and all personal user files onto OneDrive
- Introduced Microsoft Teams and designed a best-use policy that paved the way for the software to be used as the new form of primary communication between all staff
- Provided office hardware and software support for staff
- Overhauled the organisation's website to streamline the website user experience

IT Systems and Network Administrator Systechnix Ltd - Sileby, Leicestershire

Jun 2017 - Feb 2018

- Worked with clients to identify system requirements and provide suitable hardware and software solutions to plan, create and maintain a stable LAN platform
- Managed the hardware & software specifications and physical installations of servers (Windows Server 2016) for three of the largest clients
- Daily supervision of PCs, printers and servers to identify areas of performance improvement
- On call 24/7/365 in case of critical system crashes and data loss emergencies
- Displayed strong communication skills by aiding users in software and hardware troubleshooting
- Designed a new company logo, website, masthead, email signature and quotation template
- Co-designed a secure internal database to keep a concise consistent record of client data that is GDPR compliant

Sales Representative

Arc Business Interiors - Shepshed, Leicestershire

Jun 2015 - Sep 2015

- Networked with a new customer that resulted in several contracts to design large office spaces
- Promoted new products and services to new and existing customers

Cashier

Example Clothing UK - Barrow, Leicestershire

Jun 2014 - Sep 2014

Volunteering

First Aider for St John Ambulance

Dec 2014 - Dec 2016

• Chief Fundraiser Officer for my division of St John Ambulance

Oct 2015 – Jun 2017